# Curriculum Vitæ: Dr John-Patrick Stacey

me@jpstacey.info → www.jpstacey.info

#### What I can do

I have over ten years of experience of working with a number of languages, both programming and markup. I have in-depth understanding of PHP, Drupal, MySQL and CSS(3)/HTML(5), and work daily with Javascript frameworks, Apache configuration and Git.

I architect, build, optimize and launch high-profile content-managed sites in the charitable and non-profit sector. I love that I get to work for charities I care about every day. I interact closely with some clients but I'm happy with whatever the project's success requires. I negotiate and specify on-budget features, and deliver consistently to deadlines.

I lead a team of developers through technical direction, architecture advice and encouragement of team discussion and internal problem solving. I contribute to, and oversee, comprehensive internal documentation; I schedule and take part in pair programming; and I establish regular code reviews to maintain and improve the quality of work from the team.

I contribute to the open-source community. I build Drupal modules and patch bugs in others' contributions. I maintain a Bash/Drush framework which our whole team uses to develop and deploy Drupal sites using a combination of Git and the Drupal community's drush-make tool, which eliminates problems with versioning of contributed content.

I organize and present the Oxford Geek Nights, a local tech event that has run for over four years. I find and invite keynote speakers for each event, and arrange sponsorship for venue and drinks. I have spoken both at the Geek Nights and at Drupalcon Copenhagen 2010, where I led a session on automating user personas with Selenium. I attend conferences like OpenTech. I wrote two chapters of Apress' "Python 3 for Beginners" and have a clear technical style.

I can set up web servers with LAMP, Memcache and Varnish. I have installed Ubuntu Linux on a Macbook Pro. I get a kick from well-implemented version control and successful unit tests. My portable music player plays .ogg files. I am a pragmatic, excited, devoted geek.

## Relevant experience

Torchbox Ltd, Charlbury, Oxon

Tech lead Aug 2009—present Directing team of 3-8 developers, ensuring code quality and

cross-team standardization. Architecting, specifying and coding.

Senior developer May 2008<sup>1</sup>—present Advocated adoption of Drupal in Torchbox; architected/built Drupal sites and extended existing ones; also pitched to clients,

\_

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>1</sup>All dates of internal promotions are approximate.

worked on discovery process and wrote specifications.

Developer Apr 2005–Apr 2008 Built a Coldfusion framework to power several directory-based

websites; built and augmented other sites using Torchbox's proprietary CMS RationalMedia; was the sole developer on

Torchbox's first two Drupal sites.

Junior developer Jan 2005–Mar 2005 Built MLA East Midlands, combined 3-site Rational Media project.

Apress, New York, NY

Freelance writer Jan 2009—Mar 2009 Co-authored the book "Python 3 for Absolute Beginners."

Extenza ePS, Abingdon, Oxon

ePublisher Sep 2003–Dec 2004 Built QC tools in XSL to aid by-eye XML checking.

#### Websites I have worked on

**Lead, co-built** Chartered Society of Physiotherapy <a href="http://www.csp.org.uk/">http://www.csp.org.uk/</a>

and launched Greenpeace UK <a href="http://www.greenpeace.org.uk/">http://www.greenpeace.org.uk/</a>
Coeliac UK <a href="http://www.coeliac.org.uk/">http://www.coeliac.org.uk/</a>

The Joseph Rowntree Foundation <a href="http://www.jrf.org.uk/">http://www.jrf.org.uk/</a>

Advised on, Action Aid International <a href="http://actionaid.org/">http://actionaid.org/</a>

worked on and/or The Migration Observatory <a href="http://ww.migrationobservatory.ox.ac.uk/">http://ww.migrationobservatory.ox.ac.uk/</a>
Age of Stupid <a href="http://ageofstupid.net/">http://ageofstupid.net/</a>

Age of Stupid <a href="http://ageofstupid.net/">http://ageofstupid.net/</a>
University of Chester <a href="http://www.chester.ac.uk/">http://www.chester.ac.uk/</a>

### Technologies I like to use

**Ask me about:** PHP, Drupal, CSS, HTML, MySQL, jQuery, Javascript, Linux, Selenium, Git, Subversion, Python, Bash, Apache, Fabric, Django, Memcache, Varnish, Wordpress, XSL, Coldfusion, PostgreSQL, SQL Server... *in roughly that order.* 

## Qualifications

Wadham College, Oxford

Oct 1999–May 2003 DPhil (thesis in physics)
Oct 1995–Jun 1999 MPhys (first class)

Queen Elizabeth's Grammar School, Blackburn 23

Sep 1993–Jul 1995 Five A-levels: A grade Sep 1991–Jul 1993 Eight GCSEs: A grade

## **Hobbies & personal**

Cycling, music, environment, fiction reading & writing, sustainable living, local politics, current affairs.

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>2</sup>A-levels NEAB: Mathematics; Further Mathematics; Physics; Chemistry; General Studies; also OCSEB Components Maths Pure 1 & 2 (A) earlier in 1993; Physics special paper (distinction).

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>3</sup>GCSEs NEA, SEG: Mathematics; Physics; Chemistry; Biology; English; French; Latin; German; also Religious Studies (B) in 1991.